好像突然间发生了好多事
It seems like all of a sudden, so much is happening.
是啊  罗斯要结婚
I know. Ross is getting married.
菲比在做人
Phoebe's making people.
大家都在忙  只有我们坐在这里
Everybody's doing stuff. We just sit here.
要是我死了  大家只会从这张椅子的屁股印上
If I died, the only way people would know I was here...
知道我存在过
...would be by the ass print on this chair.
我们得有所作为  做一件大事
Look, we have to do something. Okay? Something huge.
我们可以去爬圣母峰 (珠穆朗玛峰)
We could climb Mount Everest.
不…不是蠢事  是大事
No, no. Not something stupid. Something huge.
不…我在录影带上看到广告
No, no, no. I saw an ad for this video.
每天都有人在爬  我们也可以去爬
People climb that thing every day. We could totally do that.
谁说不行  只不过是爬山
Why not? I mean, it's just climbing.
只不过很陡
It's just steep.
对
Yeah.
我们去攻顶  在山顶留屁股印一定很爽
We're going to Everest. Okay? It'd be nice to leave an ass print on Everest.
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
在干什么  我们要去爬圣母峰
What's up? We're gonna climb Mount Everest.
对  没错  真的
Yeah, baby. Really?
我也去问过
I looked into that.
但是要花六万元   而且可能会死
Yeah, but, I mean, it costs like $60,000, and, you know, you could die. And...
你们一定会死
And you would die.
这样啊
Oh, well.
我们可以去借圣母峰的录影带
We could get that Everest video.
对  那样就不必冒生命危险
Yeah, we could do that without, you know, risking our lives at all.
到了录影带店  我们还可以借 "虎胆龙威"
While we're down at the video store, we could rent Die Hard.
知道吗  我刚想起
Oh. You know what? I just remembered.
那个圣母峰录影带只能邮购
That Everest thing is only available through mail order.
这样啊
Oh, well.
所以你们决定留下来陪我了
So you guys will stay here and hang out with me?
对啊  对啊
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
不过我要告诉你  总有一天
But I'll tell you something. one of these days...
我们会站起来  再去借一次 "虎胆龙威"
...we're gonna get off our butts and rent Die Hard again.
没错
Yeah, we are.
老友记  第四季  第21集  邀请
Friends  S04E21  The One With The Invitation
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
决定怎样  请不请你的纳森叔叔
So, what did we decide? Does your uncle Nathan get an invite or not?
天啊  没有人喜欢他
Oh, God. Nobody likes him.
而且他好小器  他绝不会飞去伦敦的
And he's so cheap. He'd never fly to London in a million years.
好  那请他吧
Yeah, invite him.
我写得还可以吗
Hey, did I do these neat enough?
可以啊  是吗
Yeah, they're fine. Yeah?
别人问  我们就说是班写的
If anyone asks, we'll say that Ben addressed them.
喔  你也请了瑞秋
Oh. So you invited Rachel then?
对啊  干嘛不请
Sure, why not?
真的  对
Really? Yeah.
我找旧情人去一定会觉得别扭
Well, I don't think I'd be comfortable having any of my old lovers there.
等等  你觉得我们不该请她吗
Wait, wait, wait. Do you think we shouldn't invite her?
不  不  罗斯  我很喜欢瑞秋
Oh, no, no, Ross, you know I absolutely adore Rachel.
只是我觉得  怕你会尴尬
It's just that, well, I thought it might be a bit awkward for you.
不过你决定就好
But it's absolutely your decision.
还要茶吗  好
More tea? Yeah, sure.
伯爵(茶)
Earl Grey? Huh?
好  你想请谁就请谁
Fine, yeah, invite whoever you want.
我不想单身  好吗  我想再婚
I don't want to be single, okay? I just want to be married again.
我想要一百万
And I just want a million dollars.
瑞秋
Rachel?
天哪  摩妮卡  谢天谢地
Oh, God, Monica. Hi. Thank God. Hi.
各位  这是瑞秋  她也念林肯高中
Okay. Everybody, this is Rachel, another Lincoln High survivor.
这是我的朋友  钱德  菲比
This is everybody. This is Chandler and Phoebe...
和乔伊
...and Joey.
你记得我哥罗斯吗  当然记得
Do you remember my brother, Ross? Sure.
嘿  喔  天啊  嗨
Hey. Oh, God. Hi.
你或许不知道  念高中时
You know, back in high school...
我非常喜欢你
...I had a, um, major crush on you.
我知道  真的喔   好吧
I knew. You did? Oh, okay.
我以为你只当我是  摩妮卡的怪胎哥哥
I always figured you just thought I was Monica's geeky brother.
我是啊
I did. Oh.
听着  你觉得…
Listen, do you think...?
请别被我容易紧张的缺点影响
And try not to let my intense vulnerability become any kind of a factor here
改天我约你出去  你不会感到意外吧
but do you think it would be okay if I asked you out sometime maybe?
好啊
Yeah.
或许
Maybe.
好
Okay.
也许我会的
Okay, maybe I will.
我看到
See, I see, uh...
你会有一段火热恋情
...big passion in your future.
真的  对
Really? I do.
罗斯  你真好
Oh, Ross, you're so great. Aw...
别做梦了
It's never gonna happen.
我想问个问题
Okay, I have a question.
其实也不算是个问题
Well, uh, actually, it's not so much a question...
差不多算是一个疑惑
...as more of a general wondering...
疑虑
...ment.
好  好
Okay. Okay.
其实我一直想要
Um, well, for a while now, I've been wanting to, um...
对  没错  那是
Oh... Yes. Yes. That's...
你看  那只可爱的小猫
Look at that little kitty. That's right.
什么  那可爱的小猫
What? That little kitty.
All Top of the world looking
Down on creation
And the only explanation I can find
你给我听着  车在人在  车亡人亡
Listen, missy, if you want this cart, you're gonna have to take me with it.
好耶
Yes.
你看到了吗  你太猛了
Did you see that? You were incredible.
你看到了吗  全新的瑞秋诞生了
A brand-new woman, ladies and gentlemen.
谢谢  没有你我绝对办不到
Thank you. I could not have done this without you.
好  嗯
Okay, um... Uh...
还要烘衣服吗
More clothes in the dryer?
我没事  没事
I'm fine. I'm fine.
你没资格说你对我有感觉
You had no right to tell me you ever had feelings for me.
什么  我和菜莉
What? I was doing great with Julie...
原本过得很好
...before I found out about you.
我原本过得也很好
I was doing great before I found out about you.
你以为看你们在一起很好受吗
You think it's easy for me to see you with Julie?
问题的重点是我不想要这样
Well, the point is I don't need this right now.
好吗  来不及了
Okay? It's too late.
我有别人了  我很快乐  这艘船已经开了
I'm with somebody else. I'm happy. This ship has sailed.
好  你走啊  去做啊  罗斯
All right, fine. Go ahead and do that, all right, Ross?
我不需要你这艘笨船
I don't need your stupid ship.
好   很好
Good. Good.
罗斯  这是我这辈子第一次做我爱做的事
Ross do you realize this is the first time in my life I'm doing something I actually care about?
做我真正在行的事
This is the first time in my life I'm doing something that I'm actually good at.
要是你不懂
I mean. If you don't get that...
我懂  我很懂  我为你高兴
I get that. I get that bigtime. And I'm happy for you...
但我不想再跟答录机交往了
...but I'm tired of having a relationship with your answering machine.Okay,
我已经没辙了  我也是
I don't know what to do anymore. Well, neither do I.
跟马克有关吗
Is this about Mark?
我的天哪  好  没关系
Oh, my God. Okay, it's not.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
我不能为了同样的事一吵再吵
I cannot keep having this same fight over and over again, Ross.
好   你快把我逼疯了
No. You're making this too hard.
我快把你逼疯了  你要我怎么做
I'm making this too hard? What do you want me to do?
我不知道  我不知道  也许我们应该分开
I don't know. I don't know. Look, maybe we should just take a break.
你说得对  我们先分开  先冷静一下  好吗
You're right. Let's take a break. Let's cool off, okay?
去吃点冷冻优格什么的
Let's get some frozen yogurt or something.
不
No.
我是说分手
A break from us.
我们在找什么  我昨晚提到的那个女朋友
Why we're rushing? You know the girlfriend I told you about last night?
现在她情况有了变化  她想跟我复合
It turns out that she, uh, wants to get back together with me.
找到了
Oh, I found it!
太好了  对
That's so great for you guys. Yeah.
祝你复合成功  谢谢
Good luck with your girlfriend. Oh, thank you... Ah, hey.
瑞秋
Rachel!
你听到留言了吗  来得正好
You got my message? You are right on time.
你怎么说  我可以再当你的女朋友吗
So, what do you say? Can I be your girlfriend again?
当然可以
Yes, you can very much.
你给我走  滚  不要  不
I want you to leave. Get outta here! No. No.
我想留下来  我想留下来谈一谈
I wanna stay. I wanna talk about this.
好  她功夫如何
Okay! All right. How was she?
什么  她厉害吗
What? Was she good?
不要回答
Don't answer that.
你说你想谈  那就谈啊  她功夫怎么样啊
You said you wanted to talk about it. Let's talk about it. How was she?
她…
She was...
很差  什么也比不上你  不好
Awful. She was not good, not good.
不能跟你比
Nothing compared to you.
她不一样
She was different.
好的  还不一样
Good different?
没有人喜欢改变
Nobody likes change.
别再说了
Oh! Just stop.
你这么坦然认错
The way you owned up to everything...
证明你真的成长了不少
...it just showed me how much you've grown, you know?
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
I mean, my mom never thought this would work out.
她说  "出轨一次  就会有第二次 "
She was all, "Once a cheater, always a cheater."
真希望没有这四个月的空白
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
但要是时间能让你看清楚一点
But if time was what you needed just to gain a little perspective...
我们当时分手了
We were on a break!
（瑞秋葛林小姐收）
你似乎真的很喜欢她
You seem to really like her.
我能怎么办  我们说好只在一起两周
Yeah, but what am I gonna do? We both agreed that it was gonna be a two-week thing,
不要有承诺
You know? No commitment.
罗斯  那个女孩整晚都跟你的朋友
Ross, that girl just spent the entire evening talking to your friends...
嚷着要听你的事
...asking to hear stories about you...
还看摩妮卡的相册
...looking through Monica's photo albums.
如果你只想在一起两周  你才不会这么做
I mean, you don't do that if you're just in it for two weeks.
你这么想
You think? Heh.
她还有14个小时才要去机场
You've got like 14 hours until she has to be at the airport.
你却坐在走廊上
And you're sitting here in a hallway...
陪着一个28岁  嘴肿起来的老啦啦队长浪费时间
...with a 28-year-old cheerleader with a fat lip.
你说得对  对
Yeah, you're right. Yeah.
真是太好了
Oh, this is so amazing.
很难相信我哥  居然要去伦敦结婚
I can't believe my brother's getting married, and in London.
太浪漫了
It's so romantic.
想得真周到
Hey, pretty smart.
还有面巾纸
Tissue paper.
参加婚礼  当然会哭
You're at the wedding. You have to cry.
需要手帕吗  不  我有喜帖
Handkerchief? No, I got my invitation.
看啊  真可爱
Oh, look, isn't this adorable?
罗斯让班写给我的信封
Ross let Ben address mine.
哈罗  嘿
Hello. Hey.
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
你收到罗斯的婚礼喜帖了吗
Hey, did you get your invitation to Ross' wedding?
没收到
No.
放心  我可以带一位亲友  看他怎么说
Don't worry, man, I get to bring a guest. We'll show him.
太嫉妒了  你们都要去
I'm so jealous you're all going.
怀孕九个月居然不能坐飞机
I can't believe I never knew you can't fly in your third trimester.
从来都不知道  我也不知道
I never knew that. I didn't, either.
我知道
I knew that.
我也不知道  但你们的表情太喜感了
So didn't know that. But you should see your faces.
嗨  你们在干嘛  嘿
Hi, guys. What's up?
也没干嘛
We're hanging out.
这是什么  罗斯的喜帖
What's this? Is this Ross' wedding invitation?
也许该藏的是那一张
Maybe that's the one we should have actually hidden.
不  不  不必那样
Oh, no. No, you guys, come on. You don't have to do that.
我替他高兴啊
I'm happy for him.
真的  我  我很…
I am. I really... I'm... I'm ha...
我会调节的
I'll work on it.
对不起  甜心
I'm sorry, honey.
瑞秋  你会去吧
Rach, you're going to come though, aren't you?
喔  甜心  我不知道
Oh, honey, I don't know. I...
该不会  "她不去  我们就不去吧"
This isn't one of those "If she doesn't come, we don't come"?
我已经买票了
Because I already bought my ticket...
你不去才会真的很奇怪
You know what would be real weird? If you weren't there.
你就考虑下吧  我会的  我会考虑的
Just say you'll think about it, okay? No, I'll think about it. Yeah.
这是谁送的  罗斯送的
Who's this from? That's Ross'.
喔  天哪
Oh, my God.
他记得
He remembered.
记得什么
Remembered what?
好几个月前  我们经过一家古董店
It was like months ago. We were walking by this antique store.
我看到这个别针  对他说  小时候我奶奶
I saw this pin, and I told him it was just like one my grandmother had...
有一个一模一样的
...when I was a little girl. Oh.
他居然记得
I can't believe he remembered.
他肯定花了不少钱
This must have cost him a fortune.
他居然这么大方
I can't believe he did this.
罗斯 记得他大学爱上卡萝时
Ross? Remember back in college when he fell in love with Carol...
就送了她一只超贵的水晶鸭
...and bought her that ridiculously expensive crystal duck?
你刚才在说什么
What did you just say?
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
来自北京的457号班机  刚刚抵达
Flight number 457 from Beijing now arriving.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我们是老同学  毕业后就没见过
Well, Ross and I were in grad school together.We haven't seen each other since then.
到了中国  你们猜是谁主持挖掘工作
Well, I land in China. Guess who's in charge of the dig?
茱莉
Julie!
是茱莉  很棒吧
Julie! Isn't that great?
真像是  老二被踹到  腰被闪到家
Isn't that just kick-you-in-the-crotch, spit-on-your-neck fantastic?
你真好
Oh, that is so sweet.
不
No... Heh.
不  你先挂
No... Okay. No, you hang up.
不  你…好
No, you... Okay. Okay.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
你也没挂
Well you didn't hang up either
她也没挂
She didn't hang up either.
不  你挂
Okay, no.
你挂  你挂
No, you hang up.
你  你挂
You. You. Y...
罗斯  嗨
Ross, hi.
我是瑞秋
It's Rachel.
我只是打来告诉你一切都很好
I'm just calling to say that, um, everything's fine.
我很替你和你的猫
And I'm really happy for you...
高兴
...and your cat.
所以很显然  我已经放下你了
So obviously, I am over you.
我已经放下你了
I am over you.
而那样的话  我的朋友  就叫了结
And that, my friend, is what they call closure.
瑞秋  有你打的留言
Rach, I got a message from you.
完了  罗斯  挂掉  电话给我
Oh, my God, no. Hang up the phone. Give me the phone.
电话给我  电话给我...
Give me the phone, give me the phone. Give me the phone!
你放下我了
You're over me?
天哪
Oh, God.
什么你  喔  天啊
What...? You're, uh? Oh, God.
你放下我
You're over me?
你何时…
When were you...
举起我的
...under me?
基本上
Basically, ahem...
最近  我
...lately, I've, uh...
我对你有点感觉
Ahem. I've uh, sort of had feelings for you.
好  我得躺下
Okay, I need to lie down.
他跟茱莉分手了
He broke up with Julie.
快点过去拥抱她啊
Well, go hug her, for God's sakes.
真的  真的
Really? Really.
我一直都只要你  瑞秋
It's always been you, Rach.
天哪
Oh, God.
哦
Oh...
抱歉今晚还得工作
Listen, I'm sorry I had to work tonight.
没关系
Oh, that's okay.
你值得我等
You're worth the wait. Oh.
我不只是指今晚
And I don't just mean tonight.
I never dreamed That I'd meet somebody like you
I never dreamed That I'd lose somebody like you
No, I don't want to fall in love
天哪
Oh, God!
亲爱的
Oh. Honey.
没关系
Oh, that's okay.
不是  你压到果汁了
Oh, no, you just rolled over the juice box.
阿甘  请告诉我你没告诉瑞秋
Gunther, please tell me you didn't say anything to Rachel...
我跟复印店女生的事吧
...about me and the girl from the copy place.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不该说吗
Was I not supposed to?
是你要分手的  记得吗
You're the one who ended it.
因为我很气你  不是因为我不爱你了
Yeah, because I was mad at you. Not because I stopped loving you.
你还爱我
You still love me?
没有
No.
什么意思  你想复合吗
What does this mean? What do you...? I mean, do you want to get back together?
不是…也许吧
No. Maybe.
我不…知道  什么
I don't... I don't know. What?
我只是觉得
I just... I feel...
我居然会想跟你复合  我们根本就完了
I can't believe I even thought of getting back together with you. We are so over.
无所谓
Fine by me!
顺便告诉你  这种事并不常见
And, hey, just so you know, it's not that common...
并非男人都会这样  这是很严重的
...it doesn't happen to every guy, and it is a big deal!
我就知道
I knew it!
（瑞秋葛林小姐会参加 不会参加）
瑞秋来了  她是不是很美啊
Rachel's coming up. Doesn't she look pretty, Jack?
天哪
Oh, my God.
你知道这是什么  这是我们准备要去参加舞会
You know what this is, This is us getting ready for the prom. Oh!
知道吗  这种带子别看了
You know what? We don't have to watch this.
当然要看   拜托啦
Yeah, we do.Come on.
拍下摩妮卡
Get a shot of Monica.
等等  怎么拉远
Wait, how do you zoom out?
有了
There she is.
快闭嘴  上镜头会多10磅
Shut up. The camera adds 10 pounds.
那到底有多少个镜头对着你啊
Huh, so how many cameras are actually on you?
爸  关掉啦
Dad, turn it off.
我关了
It is off. Yeah.
对吧  罗斯
Right, Ross?
好帅啊  麦克风头
Looking good, Mr. Kotter.
我没舞伴不能去舞会  时间来不及了
I can't go to my own prom without a date. I can't. It's too late.
要是你不去  我也不想去了
If you're not going, then I don't wanna go either.
我有个好主意
I have a wonderful idea.
你带瑞秋去参加舞会
You should take Rachel to the prom.
看够了  关掉吧
We've seen enough. Let's turn it off.
不要啦  好  那我不看  行吧
I want to see. Fine, I'm not going to watch, all right?
走吧  小伙子
Come on, kid. Let's go.
你好帅
Are you handsome.
去让他们看看
Let's show them.
行了  瑞秋  不管你好了没
Okay, Dad. Rachel, ready or not.
解救你的白马王…
Here comes your knight in shining...
再见  不用等我们  奇普  快点
Bye. Don't wait up. Okay, Chip, let's go.
天哪
Oh, dear.
要怎么关掉
Jack, how do I turn this off?
不敢相信你居然这样做
I can't believe you did that.
对  我就
Yeah, well...
看吧  他是她的龙虾
See? He's her lobster.
不会吧
No.
你真的不去  对
You're really not going? Yeah.
我会很难面对
It's just going to be too hard.
毕竟
You know, I mean...
他是罗斯
...it's Ross.
我怎么能看着他结婚
How can I watch him get married?
这样最好  真的
You know? It's just for the best, you know? It is.
而且总得有人陪菲比
Plus somebody's got to stay here with Phoebe.
到时她的肚子会很大
She's going to be pretty big by then...
她会需要别人绑鞋带
...and she'll need someone to help her tie her shoes.
她要生的时候送她去医院
Drive her to the hospital in case she goes into labor.
你没有车
You don't have a car.
驾照也过期了
And your license expired.
看吧  事情那么多  时间又那么少
Yeah. See, there's so much to do, and I have so little time to do it in.
你们看  你们看
All right, check it out. Check this out.
这里有完整的博物馆录影带
It says there's a place you can go to rent videos of all the museums.
"几乎如同身临其境"
"It's almost as good as being there."
更棒  你不能只穿内裤去博物馆
It's better. You can't go to a museum in your underwear.
可以  但以后你会被博物馆封杀的
Well, you could, but probably just the one time.
我们可以去租所有景点的录影带
I bet we could get videos of all the sights...
然后搬台放影机到旅馆的房间  我们就不必出房间了
...get a VCR in our hotel room, we'd never even have to go outside.
那样的话   一定要租 "虎胆龙威"
If we do that, we've got to rent Die Hard.
听说英国版本的更好看
Oh-ho, I bet the British version is good.